The Count is a development
of Chaplin's early Keystone comedy...
Caught in a Cabaret and
a anticipation od The Ring...
The Idle Class and
City Lights.
In all of these films Charlie
impersonated wealthy men...
to draw humorous if pointed
contrasts between rich and poor...
one of him favorite themes.
The fifth Chaplin Mutual, The Count
was released September 4, 1916.
THE COUNT
CAST
Measurements: Neck 12, Ear 1 1/2,
Mouth 2, Waste 5 feet, Finger 1
Miss Moneybags
Dear Mrs. Moneybags:
Sorry I cannot attend
your dance tonight.
Althought we have never met,
I'm sure I shall love
your walthy daughter...
...at first sight.
Count Broko.
"Shh! I'm supposed to be a
Count. You can be my secretary."
"Delighted, Count Broko!"
"This is my secretary!"
Watermelon!
"You keep away from
Miss Moneybags!"
Count Broko
"They are imposters!"